# JP DILLINGHAM

## **Software Engineer**

E: jpdillingham@gmail.com | P: (309) 749-8075 | w: http://dillingham.ws | LinkedIn: jpdillingham | GitHub: jpdillingham

#### **Summary**

Software engineer with 10 years of experience executing and managing software projects in the Industrial Automation MES/MOM (Manufacturing Execution System/Manufacturing Operations Management) space with involvement from first customer contact to completion. Experience managing and mentoring both direct reports and members of project teams across software, systems, mechanical and electrical engineering disciplines.

Wide breadth of experience in software development with most projects including both hardware and software elements. Primarily focused on full stack web and desktop/server application development in Microsoft C# .NET and SQL server. Fully versed in modern software development methodologies including Test Driven Development (TDD), unit testing, Continuous Integration (CI), and source control (SVN, Git). Active in the Open Source community with projects in C# and Java.

#### **Experience**

#### **Senior Software Engineer**

Grantek Systems Integration | December 2015 – Present

Functioning as a senior level software engineer responsible for mid to large scale Industrial Automation MES/MOM software project specification, architecture, technical planning, and execution.

Responsible for the technical engineering oversight and mentoring of less senior engineers while also contributing individually in software development and project execution, and with respect to new technologies, research and development, and the definition and implementation of standards and practices for the organization.

#### **Open Source Software Developer**

December 2015 - Present

Actively participating in Open Source Software development during off-work hours with repositories written in C# and Java. Member of the Free Software Foundation and the Open Source Initiative.

#### **Engineering Manager, Manufacturing Software Systems**

Grantek Systems Integration | March 2014 – December 2015 (1 year 10 months)

Responsible for general management of the Manufacturing Software Systems department of the Grantek Chicago office, including the management, scheduling, and career growth of four direct reports.

Responsible for the quotation, engineering oversight, and management of Industrial Automation MES/MOM software projects with teams as large as eight, spanning multiple disciplines and involving multiple customer sites and subcontractors. Functioned as Lead Developer and Technical Lead on the majority of managed projects.

#### **Software Engineer**

Grantek Systems Integration | August 2007 – March 2014 (6 years 8 months)

Responsible for the design, implementation, commissioning, and support of Industrial Automation MES/MOM software systems with an emphasis on data collection, storage, and reporting. Independently delivered several successful projects with minimal supervision.

### **Education**

#### **Bachelor of Science, Computer Science**

Western Illinois University | 2003 – 2007 | 4.0 Major, 3.8 Cumulative GPA, With Honors

Member of honor societies Phi Kappa Phi and Upsilon Pi Epsilon, received the "Outstanding Senior of 2007" award for the Computer Science department.

## Skills

**Software Development:** OOP, UML, Design patterns, C#/.NET, Java, Full-Stack web development, SQL, and Industrial-specific SCADA and MES packages. Unit testing, continuous integration and source control (SCM).

Systems Engineering: Virtualization, Windows server administration, Linux/UNIX, hardware specification.

**Project Management:** Requirements modeling and documentation, Design documentation, task and resource planning, Microsoft Project/Visio.